<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:lj="http://www.livejournal.org/rss/lj/1.0/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
	<title>Izzati_Kas</title>
	<item>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">000</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 01:14:00 EST</pubDate>
		<title>It_is_easier_to_maintain_good_relationships_in_social_networking_sites_such_as_Facebook</title>
		<link>000</link>
		<description> Yes, taking the time off to call or e-mail the recipient is also good enough but won't the receiver feel a little dissapointed?
 For example your mother's birthday.
 You should traitionally make time for it every year so that you can celebrate it.
 Your mother will feel touched and love you even more every year.
 Would a 10 second call to your mother to say "Happy Birthday Mum!
 I love you!" be the same a simple 3 hour appearance for your mother on her special day?
</description>
		<comments url="000">
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="001">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">hannah_h</user>
				<text> •Social networking sites entice people to spend more time online and less time interacting face-to-face.•The sites offer many time wasting activities that supplant more productive activities.
 Teens spend an average of4 to 6 hours hours per week on social networking sites.In the study, which randomly selected more than 24,000 undergraduate students from 14 Minnesota colleges, 30 percent of students reported “excessive screen time” in front of their TV or computer.
 Students who reported screen time as a problem had an average GPA of 3.04, compared to 3.27 for students who said they don't struggle with too much screen time."
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="001" parent-url="001" url="002">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DMileyC</user>
				<text> then why are you still online debating and not debating face to face?HAHA :)
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="003">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">WongMunYoke</user>
				<text> Why do you need to travel around the world?
 With advances in today's technology, you can use a webcam or a 3G phone to see and talk to people overseas.
 If you subscribe to a line, it could as well be free.
 It is almost the same as meeting them in person, but saving lots of money at the same time.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="004">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">hannah_h</user>
				<text> •The arguments are responded as; firstly meeting new people online is a bad choice due to the risk of identifying stranger’s real role.•Secondly, knowing online friends is not the same as real friend in reality.•Thirdly, social networking sites may lead to break downs of existing relationships.•Every pro side can turn into con side; it depends on how user participates in the online activities.•The attitudes they react, the manners they have, the purposes they intend to, all those can form and result in a very different answers in real-life.•In a meaningful conclusion, there are no clear guidelines to determine whether pros or cons sides are on the best beneficial to users.
 Therefore, virtual communities and social networks do not only enhance but also destroy people’s relationships in real-life
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="005">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">MichelleVong</user>
				<text> If you are don't even want to speak to someone in person, then what is the point of maintaining a good relationship online?
 You are missing the human element.
 When you keep a good relationship online but don't even acknowledging them face to face, then you might as well be strangers.
 How is that maintaining a good relationship?
 Maintaining a good relationship is being able to talk to the person as if you've known them forever and not acting like strangers.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="006">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Cassang</user>
				<text> I disagree with this.
 People are often more harsh in social networking sites.
 They are not who they really are.
 Creating more misunderstandings in between.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="006" parent-url="006" url="007">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">YiXin</user>
				<text> no thats not true.
 you see . when you talk on fb , when you say smthing wrong . you can backspace before you press enter but in real life . you cannot.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="007" parent-url="007" url="008">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">sheadou</user>
				<text> but they press the enter button too fast.
 and u tend to say more harsh words online as u don see the face of the person so u just say whatever u want.
 without even knowing the seriousness of it!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="007" parent-url="007" url="009">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Cassang</user>
				<text> yes that might be true.
 which means things that you actually wanted to say, you are not saying.
 Instead you are beating around the bush.
 This does not solve the problem, you are just avoiding it.
 Backspace?
 In face to face, we can explain things easier.
 and in a better way
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="007" parent-url="007" url="010">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Cassang</user>
				<text> yes that might be true.
 which means things that you actually wanted to say, you are not saying.
 Instead you are beating around the bush.
 This does not solve the problem, you are just avoiding it.
 Backspace?
 In face to face, we can explain things easier.
 and in a better way
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="010" parent-url="010" url="011">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DMileyC</user>
				<text> harsh?
 How can people be harsh on net?
 you can only scold bad words and put CAPS but when in real life you can beat and shout at people.
 So maintaining good relationship in social networking siters such as Facebook is easier then face to face.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="011" parent-url="011" url="012">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">WendyL</user>
				<text> Then you tell me did Miley Cyrus use Facebook ? Did yangmi ? :D HAHA .
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="012" parent-url="012" url="013">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DMileyC</user>
				<text> Hello wendy?
 i say that if you think social network are not good then don't use it but miley cyrus and yangmi support social network so they use.
 Even yangmi also use facebook.
 HAHA..
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="013" parent-url="013" url="014">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">WendyL</user>
				<text> I don't think you seems to get what i mean . I SAID : DID REAL MILEY CYRUS USE FACEBOOK ? DID REAL YANGMI USE FACEBOOK ? DID THEY ???
 Don't tell me yes i'll faint ..
 I will add her asap ..
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="014" parent-url="014" url="015">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DMileyC</user>
				<text> Miley Cyrus do really have her onw facebook and twitter.
 She go to twitter almost everyday to communicate with her fans!
 She admitted that twitter helps her to know what her fans is all thinking about!!!!!!!!!!!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="005" parent-url="005" url="016">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">vivienlai</user>
				<text> Although this is a good point, however if you have a good time management, no matter how addictive it is, you can control yourself.
 so like if your done your homework and then on your computer, it will not affect your schoolwork.Not releasing any of your personal information will not harm yourself thus it can be safe and not dangerous.saying hi to the opposite party can test about your social networking skills.
 it is not about whether you want to know them or not.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="016" parent-url="016" url="017">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">MichelleVong</user>
				<text> Michelle 2E2,How do you know that people might even bother to manage their time well?
 Not everybody is independent and strong enough to resist the temptations of the internet.
 And besides, when a person is addicted to the internet, it won't be easy to stop.
 I mean, if addiction is so easy to stop, then the world would not need rehabitation centres right?
 And another point, even if you create a time table for yourself, how do you make sure you follow it?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="018">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">PrayerFails</user>
				<text> Yes, I heard rumors that Facebook is the ultimate spy tool for the CIA.
 However, the CIA is unauthorized to spy on American Citizens, but we all know that the CIA does whatever the Fuck it wants.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="018" parent-url="018" url="019">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">VenusEve</user>
				<text> The American Government probably DOES spy on us via Facebook.However,it's like taking a crap: it is unpleasant but necessary....as long as one is not behaving in an abberrant fashion it will proabably be okay.I hope it will anyway.Otherwise we are all in very much a screwed postion in this country.There ARE some apps where to use them they ask for permission to mine your details such as I.D. and friend's list and such things, but you have the option to deny that request, and forego the app.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="019" parent-url="019" url="020">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">PrayerFails</user>
				<text> American government spying via CIA or NSA on United States citizens is illegal.
 Making an analogy to taking a crap is really bad.
 So, basically, the government breaking its own laws is fine as long as it is not an exuberant fashion.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="014" parent-url="014" url="021">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DMileyC</user>
				<text> People!
 we are talking about using social networking site to maintain good relationship is more convenient than face to face, not giving up your real social life.
 When you say that you never spend your time sharpening your communication skills but wasting your time on social media like Facebook all those, you mean that once you are online you can't talked to people anymore?
 It is more convenient to chat online since people have invented phone and ipad and wifi.
 Do you want to waste your money just to buy an air ticket to a foreign country every year to chat face to face to maintain good relationship?Do you think the money is worth?If we people are maintaining our relationship through face to face, we are going back to ice age.....We are not improving but deproving.OMG :)
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="008" parent-url="008" url="022">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DMileyC</user>
				<text> Misunderstanding?
 Can you give some example?
 Our argument here is about social networking sited is easier to maintain good relationship not type out everything you want to say.
 Even when people talk face to face, they tend to start arguing easily,however when you are online chatting, you can't start a argument easily because you can't see the people's expression.
 ;0
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="022" parent-url="022" url="023">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">WendyL</user>
				<text> See ? This is a real life example . You are debating her in a good way but she might misunderstand in a bad way . She might possibly start a argument because of this too even without expression ~
</text>
			</comment>
		</comments>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>