<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:lj="http://www.livejournal.org/rss/lj/1.0/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
	<title>Devin10</title>
	<item>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">000</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 01:14:00 EST</pubDate>
		<title>Should_Puerto_Rico_become_a_State</title>
		<link>000</link>
		<description> Personally, No.
 I think it shouldn't be considered a state in the United States because, the political cost to create another state can have a huge after affect on our future economic problems.
 They wouold demand more benefits than other states and their presence could tilt the balance of power away from fiscal conservatives battling to trim the bloated welfare state.
 And anyway, we would have to put a extra star on there.
 Would that look right?
</description>
		<comments url="000">
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="001">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">BecW313</user>
				<text> First off, Puerto Rico has rejected becoming a state three times since becoming a commonwealth of the United States, so the matter is not simply Americans rejecting Puerto Rico as a state but as a matter that concerns both the United States and Puerto Rico.
 On the topic of economic advantages, statehood could cost the citizens of the United States a great deal in taxes.
 Since the average Puerto Rican family income is less than one half that of our poorest state's citizens, statehood would require an extensive federal funding; over two-thirds of Puerto Rico's population lives below the federal poverty level.
 The per capita personal income is only $8,000 compared to $18,000 in the U.S.'s poorest state, Mississippi.
 As a commonwealth, the federal government has done its best to boost Puerto Rico's economy; these attempts are nothing more than attempts the economy's success has always been short-lived.
 Yes, America may be one enormous melting pot, but that does not mean we must adopt the homeland of every culture that sets foot in the United States.
 If that were possible and we followed through, planet Earth would no longer be simply Earth, but the United Earth of America.
 The United States have served well to hold the many cultures of the Earth without actually becoming a part of that country.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="002">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">vmich73</user>
				<text> For one thing, all you talked about is how we would benefit from Puerto Rico becoming a state.
 What about them?
 There aren't nearly as many benefits or the Puerto Ricans as there are for us.
 It harms their culture, one of the biggest things in Puerto Rico.
 They would have to make English their primary language when only about a quarter of Puerto Ricans speak English fluently.
 Teaching the majority of the population how to speak English wouldn't be an easy task and it definitely affects their culture.
 The Puerto Ricans would also be hurt economically.
 Although we (Americans) may gain from this new state, it would just hurt them because there is a significant difference between their economy and ours.
 Their wages and bills are exceptionally smaller than ours.
 A sudden transition to higher bills could create economic unstableness for the Puerto Ricans therefore causing more problems for the United States because we would have to make up for the problems there.
 Making Puerto Rico a state wouldn’t be nearly as easy as you make it seem, especially since we are dealing with plethora of people who do not want to become part of the United States of America.
 They would much rather stay on their own.
 So think about it, is it worth putting all of the states effort into making Puerto Rico a state when its own people don’t want that?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="002" parent-url="002" url="003">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">brycer2012</user>
				<text> English is actually one of the official languages of Puerto Rico.
 Although many speak Spanish, they are taught English from elementary school to high school and even into college.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="003" parent-url="003" url="004">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">romero</user>
				<text> I disagree.
 I'm an English teacher in Puerto Rico and have lived here for more than twenty years and let me tell you 80% of my students do not speak English.
 At most, 20 percent speak English and that's because they at one time had lived in the United States mainland.
 Go to any government office here on the island and the clerks will speak to you in Spanish.
 All transactions are conducted in Spanish.
 English is spoken more at tourist attractions--hotels, fine restaurants--but rarely is it spoken in other domains of life.
 Puerto Ricans are very proud of their Spanish roots and the Spanish language and when asked, the majority will answer that they are Puerto Rican, not American.So even though it is true that both English and Spanish are recognized as being official languages of Puerto Rico, that is just on paper.
 In reality, Spanish is the first and primary language on the island.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="004" parent-url="004" url="005">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">brycer2012</user>
				<text> I understand what you're saying, but who ever said they would have to learn to speak English if they became part of America?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="006">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">vmich73</user>
				<text> Though they may be treated like a state in some cases, they aren't yet and most likely want to keep it that way for now at least.
 This is why they have voted three times to stay the way they are and not join the states.
 Be it political reasons or social, they don't desire to be a state and gain the benefits of the states.
 Personally I think that what we consider benefits could be bad for them.
 They may use the same currency as we do, but the amount that they pay and charge for items is exceedingly different than that of the United States.
 We may around twenty to thirty dollars on water bills and they pay less than ten in some cases.
 Although they may be close to statehood, the differences could cause economic issues for Puerto Rico and maybe even the states.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="007">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Piglet915</user>
				<text> There is nothing wrong with changing the flag or redesigning it, but it would cost a lot of money and what about Puerto Rico?
 Are they suppose to just give up their flag and accept ours just like that?
 Besides, making Puerto Rico become a state would completely shatter their economy and require a lot of things.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="001" parent-url="001" url="008">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">vmich73</user>
				<text> She is right.
 Making Puerto Ricans learn the English language when most of them have only known Spanish all their life is more than it's worht.
 I know that if someone was telling me that the primary language in Texas was going to be Spanish from now on, I wouldn't be very happy.
 It's not as much have to learn the language(which is difficult in itself) as much as the fact that it takes away from the Puerto Rican culture.
 As she said, their language is a large part of the Puerto Rican culture and taking away their language could be hurtful to their culture.
 Not only that but it would be rather difficult and expensive to convert the 'state' to English.
 Any signs and stores would have to be changed to English.
 Imagine the expenses on the buisnesses.
 The amount of money that it would cost simply for a restaurant to change all of their menus to the English language would surely cost financial issues for the small buisnesses.
 So I agree that we should not make Puerto Rico a state.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="008" parent-url="008" url="009">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">robo</user>
				<text> I don't know where the statistics are coming from but i am pretty sure they are wrong.1.
 English and Spanish have been official languages since 19022.
 English is taught from first through twelfth grade3.
 50% of all Puerto Ricans over the age of 5 speak English and Spanish4.
 85% of Post -Secondary school students speak English and Spanish5.
 Federal courts and agencies use English6.
 Local governmental affairs are conducted in English and Spanish7.
 English is the language of CommerceThe information above came directly from a Puerto Rico goverment website.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="001" parent-url="001" url="010">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Josiah</user>
				<text> Techinically "forcing" the Puerto Rican territory to learn the English language would be a good thing.
 English is the predominant language used for trade and business, and giving Puerto Ricans the opportunity to learn it in a school system would be beneficial.
 Plus, its not as though they would have to give up any of their previous culture.
 According to your statistics, it sounds like they actually need help learning it.
 Besides, I think English is already being taught in Puerto Rican grade schools, which makes sense, because it really wouldnt be practical for a U.S. territory to not have that opportunity, would it?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="001" parent-url="001" url="011">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">JoeFK</user>
				<text> I think this is a reasonable response, but fortunatly statistics say that in the near future (somewhere between now and 2012) that the main language in several states is going to be Spaglish, so they won't have to force them to learn a completely new laguage.
 Isn't the reason we have Spanish class is so that we can learn to speak spanish?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="001" parent-url="001" url="012">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jwong</user>
				<text> The reasonable implementation of a nationwide decree that entails that certain conditions and changes be made by the public should not be an obstruction in the decision to pass that decree.
 If Congress failed to pass laws that required a large amount of people to change a major part of their lives, then the Amendment banning slavery would never have been enacted.
 Therefore, the argument that incorporating Puerto Rico into our 51st state and requiring the people to learn English is wrong is invalid for English is already one of the primary languages of the world and having them learn it would provide more benefits than negatives.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="012" parent-url="012" url="013">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Piglet915</user>
				<text> One can't compare abolishing slavery to making Puerto Rico a state.
 Slavery caused suffering; Puerto Rico not being a state is not making anyone suffer.
 In fact, its helping the Puerto Rican economy.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="001" parent-url="001" url="014">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">robo</user>
				<text> The English argument is invalid, Puertorricans study English as a second language from elementary school threw High school.
 Also we have to take English courses in college(9-18 credits).
 I am not sure where do you get the statistic number of 90% of the high school graduates dont speak well?
 Remember English is a second language for us so we will have some difficulty with pronunciation but we can communicate in English.
 I can speak and writte in 3 languages and i have to say is not easy to do so.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="015">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">robo</user>
				<text> They do pay taxes, some of the companied didn't pay taxes when the 936 law was in effect that law is not in play anymore.Companies left Puerto Rico when NAFTA was signed.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="016">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">MelanieD15</user>
				<text> Many states have their own rich history and culture.
 Hawaii and Louisiana are just a two of the states that have vastly different and enriched cultures, and they have both upheld their original traditions, even though they are unified under the United States.
 Saying that Puerto Rico will lose their unique and wonderful way of life if they were to join us, is far from true.
 No state in our country has lost its culture by joining the United States.
 On the fourth day of April Alabama has a legal holiday of Confederate Memorial Day, Hawaii, still celebrates many of it's original holiday's, even Prince Jonah Kuhio Kalanianaole Day on March 26, and that day goes back to when they were ruled by monarchs, Louisiana, still celebrates Mardi Gras, which is a holiday from back when it was a colony under France's rule, Maine has Patriot Day, and here in Texas we celebrate Battle of the Flowers.
 These are all things that were unique to the culture before the territory became a state, and that are still in affect today.
 Therefore saying that Puerto Rico will lose its customs and fruitful culture, like you said they would, is not true.
 Their culture will be upheld just like the culture of all the other fifty states.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="017">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">NickBG</user>
				<text> The United States is a melting pot of cultures.
 Puerto Rico's culture wont be disrupted but instead be shared with other cultures and races.
 It is not a guarantee that Puerto Rico's economy will suffer from becoming a state.
 The joining of their economy and ours may proof fruitful
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="018">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Banned</user>
				<text> Quentin drives a Corolla sport.
 He can't be wrong.
 And apparently I have to make this longer, to cut down on dumb jokes or something.
 This is ridiculous, and I am highly offended.
 I also am hungry.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="019">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">myraclem</user>
				<text> Its true that Puerto Rico is rich in culture, but why limit it just to Puerto Rico.
 As a Puerto Rico native you should want to share your culture with everyone.
 We share ours with them, so they should share theirs with us.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="020">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">ahouse92</user>
				<text> I agree strongly with this statement, it would seem as if the United States were seeking more ground for expansion or you can say power hungry if you will.
 The country is afraid of being viewed as an enemy and this will strengthen their fear.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="020" parent-url="020" url="021">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">MelanieD15</user>
				<text> One could also say that America is a power hungry, world domination seeking country based on the war we are fighting right now.
 It is not "power hungry" as you say if they country is already in a sense ours to begin with.
 They follow our governing customs almost to a t. Power hungry can only be used to describe our country when it comes to forcing our policies on other countries who want nothing to do with us.
 If Puerto Rico did not want to be a part of us, they would not map their way of governing, and ultimate political goals after our own.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="022">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">trichardson</user>
				<text> I cannot believe I am even acknowledging this catastrophe of an argument with a comment.
 Puerto Rico is trying to bamboozle America.
 If they think they can rest idly under the protective wing of America and not take part in our government or pay taxes, then they have another thing coming.
 Furthermore I was under the impression Americans still believed in Manifest Destiny.
 How can Congress possibly fathom expansion in the west if they cannot in-doctrine Puerto Rico into the union?Puerto Ricans need not dread losing their culture upon being annexed into the US.
 Many would remain in Puerto Rico and cancel out the chance of running into citizens trying to reform them.As for the other Spanish countries fearing that, "They're next," they can consider this a fair warning, because quite frankly they are next.
 When America inevitably strikes out in an effort of global conquest every foreign state will have its' populous subjugated into slavery.
 Puerto Rico would be wise to take this opportunity to join team USA and avoid a future of indentured servitude and oppression.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="013" parent-url="013" url="023">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">brycer2012</user>
				<text> Your first argument is all the more reason to make them part of the U.S. Why should the citizens pay for people who aren't citizens and don't pay taxes to get special privileges.I think a new flag would be cool.
 It gives us a chance to make it cooler.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="013" parent-url="013" url="024">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">vmich73</user>
				<text> Actually America does have an official language, English.
 meaning that Puerto Rico would have to make English their primary language also.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="024" parent-url="024" url="025">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">MelanieD15</user>
				<text> Yes, but in America, the Spanish langue is rapidly rising.
 Already in Texas, you see that a preponderance of signs and advertisements have been converted to Spanish.
 This is not just true for Texas.
 Any state bordering Mexico has a high Spanish speaking population and if Americans do not believe we should keep everything in English, even though it is our most spoken langue, and believe instead to accommodate the immigrants and their needs instead, we can easily do it for Puerto Rico as well.
 My mother’s parents emigrated from Puerto Rico.
 She has nieces and nephews that have graduated high school from the country and they are fluent in both Spanish and English.
 The school systems insist upon teaching in both Spanish and English.
 Not only in Puerto Rico, but here in Texas and in California, there is a massive number of the population speaking Spanish.
 If you go to SAISD, most of the kids speak very little to no English and their parents most likely speak none.
 Same as in areas in California.
 America can easily accommodate their langue needs.
 Look around you when you go out in San Antonio, in some areas Spanish signs come before English.
 And even still in other areas there are no English signs.
 Many businesses and education institutes already cater to langue barriers, our own school offers ESL (English as a Second Langue), and so it would be easy for Puerto Ricans to get along in the United States, even without knowing English.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="024" parent-url="024" url="026">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">brycer2012</user>
				<text> Actually, America doesn't have an official language.
 English is the dominant language, but nowhere does it say Americans have to know how to speak English.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="024" parent-url="024" url="027">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">robo</user>
				<text> If you are calling the United States "America" you will be surprised to know that the United States does not have an official language, the country is considered a multilingual country.
 The senate tried to make English the official language of the United States a couple of times and it was rejected.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="013" parent-url="013" url="028">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">10Kmille</user>
				<text> Well don't you pay for milk?
 Yes, in Puerto Rico they do get the same things without paying taxes but they also don't get to vote even though they are being ran by the U.S. government.
 The flag can look weird as long as the people here have to pay taxes so should they.
 Make them a state!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="013" parent-url="013" url="029">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">glori</user>
				<text> You are wrong in the majority of what you have stated here.
 First, the majority of us (puertorrican) do know English.
 Second, we DO pay taxes and we have many industries like Tylenol among others that have to pay federal taxes and the only beneficiaries of those earnings is the US government.
 Who's getting the milk for free?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="013" parent-url="013" url="030">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Stephanie93</user>
				<text> Actually, they learn English from first grade to college.:)It's really not that different from American culture.
 They speak English, use the same currency as us, and understand our system of government.
 They even have a spot in Congress, although as of now they do not have an official vote.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="030" parent-url="030" url="031">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Piglet915</user>
				<text> I've actually met tons of people from Puerto Rico (at my old school), most of them did not know english and the ones who did knew very little, not even enough to understand simple things.
 It is true that people tell them English will be vital to their education, however most do not learn the language anyway.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="031" parent-url="031" url="032">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">vmich73</user>
				<text> The language is not something that can be forced upon them either.
 Even if many of them do know english and America is being better suited to accomodate those who do not speak much english, it will still cause need from some potentially unwelcomed change.
 You can neccesarily make someone learn something that they don't feel is neccessary.
 It could be more problematic than helpful.
 Then again it could be the other way around.
 There is really no way to know.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="031" parent-url="031" url="033">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">glori</user>
				<text> i am puertorican, i can assure you we know english and spanish.
 So do not assume we do not know how to speak English, please don't generalize.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="000" parent-url="000" url="034">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Banned</user>
				<text> You're not Quentin, there's no way you're right.
 I mean come on, this is ridiculous.
 Let's get real.
 You're argument is false and therefore to rectify this situation I attribute your response to be an act of insanity.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="000" parent-url="000" url="035">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">brycer2012</user>
				<text> If they became a state they would receive all of those things.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="032" parent-url="032" url="036">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Stephanie93</user>
				<text> Today when I got home, I talked to my dad about his opinion on the matter.
 He is a native born Puerto Rican, and a U.S. citizen (of course) but he resides in the United States.
 He has served our country for almost 30 years, and has a lot of family still residing in Puerto Rico, so I think his point of view is valid.
 He told me that there are many factors that go into the whole debate.First of all, one of the main reasons they have rejected statehood is politics.
 Puerto Rico has a history of voting Democrat, so it all fluctuates.
 When there is a majority of Republicans in power, they want to hold it, and therefore would not like Puerto Rico to become a state.
 On the other hand, it would take a majority of Republican votes in Puerto Rico for statehood, so the only problem is that we have yet to reach that odd balance in power between the two governments and the two parties.Puerto Rico is also a major tourist attraction.
 It holds the only protected rainforest in American control; El Yunque.
 Also, they are major producers of important goods that we use: rice, coffee, sugar, and many others.
 They trade mainly with us anyways; why not just cut out the middle-man, so to speak?As for the language barrier, unless you've been there you may not know that almost all Puerto Ricans actually speak fluent English; they are taught it since the beginning of gradeschool.
 They even share the same currency as us.
 So that is the least of our issues in this debate.
 What we really need to focus on is whether they want to or not, and whether it is beneficial to us.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="036" parent-url="036" url="037">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">robo</user>
				<text> I have to agree with everything you say, the only reason staehood is voted down is because of politis and sometimes missinformation, also the referendums are tricky and they include options like statehood, independent, comonweath, none, ect.I think that the referendums are a joke, I voted on one referendum in P.R and rerally I dont understand the way the referendums are done.
 Yo
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="038">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Bohemian</user>
				<text> U.S. because factories would set up shot in Puerto Rico as they could sucker them into working for minimum wage.What prevents them from doing that now?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="039">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">glori</user>
				<text> are you kidding, poverty stricken??
 There is more poverty in many other states than in Puerto Rico, I see you have never visited the island.
 Poor You
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="040">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">ISAAC5000</user>
				<text> HAVE YOU EVER VISITED PUERTO RICO?
 BECAUSE THATS THE MOST STUPID THING I HAVE EVER HEARD
</text>
			</comment>
		</comments>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>