<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:lj="http://www.livejournal.org/rss/lj/1.0/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
	<title>usps</title>
	<item>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">000</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 01:14:00 EST</pubDate>
		<title>Should_health_care_be_free_in_the_U_S_A</title>
		<link>000</link>
		<description> Most third-world countries have free health care because the United States of America pays for it!
 the only shame is in your heart that your country can never do enough for the rest of the world.you hate your country.
</description>
		<comments url="000">
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="000" parent-url="000" url="001">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Pineapple</user>
				<text> Can you back that statement up, oh pretty please?
 I'd appreciate it.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="000" parent-url="000" url="002">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Saffron</user>
				<text> Wow, your argument literally made me laugh -- mostly due to your last point.Care to give me any facts that back up your hypothesis?
 ;] The United States donates about 13b a year, Japan donates about 10b a year...I don't think that's enough to pay health care for every third-world nation on earth.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="002" parent-url="002" url="003">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Your numbers are wrong!Fiscal Year 2010 Congressional Budget Justification for Foreign OperationsThe U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and the U.S. Department of State must be fully empowered and funded to confront the multi-dimensional challenges that face the United States today – from working with allies to thwart terrorism, to spreading health and prosperity in places of human suffering.
 To meet these challenges, the FY 2010 request reflects President Obama’s commitment to strengthen U.S. foreign assistance capacity by significantly increasing the core programming, policy, and management capabilities of the State Department and USAID.The resources in this request put the United States on a path to double U.S. foreign assistance by 2015, thereby providing the resources needed to help the world’s weakest states reduce poverty, combat global health threats, develop markets, govern peacefully, and expand democracy worldwide.
 The FY 2010 Function 150 International Affairs request totals $53.9 billion, an increase of 9 percent over the FY 2009 total, which includes both enacted and requested emergency supplemental funding.
 The FY 2010 Foreign Operations request for USAID, the Department of State and other foreign affairs agencies totals $36.7 billion, an increase of 8 percent over the FY 2009 total.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="003" parent-url="003" url="004">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">freedomrules</user>
				<text> No the U.S.A does not pay for it where did you go to school?and don't you even say Harvard.Plus it doesn't sound like his ashamed of his country it sounds like YOU hate the U.S.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="004" parent-url="004" url="005">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> "No the U.S.A does not pay for it where did you go to school?"The U.S.A. Spends Billions in foreign Aid!
 Billions every year, and if its not going into the pockets of tin pot Dictators its going to the welfare of the citizens of the country receiving the aid.As for my schooling, read your post, correct your grammar and shove Harvard up your A.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="006">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Akulakhan</user>
				<text> Then which is your opinion, government run or privatized?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="006" parent-url="006" url="007">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">PrayerFails</user>
				<text> Government interference in the economy can be most harmful; however, government health care is the most equitable form because health care is really a matter of right rather than privileged especially in a rich society.
 Health care is one of few interventions of government support.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="007" parent-url="007" url="008">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Akulakhan</user>
				<text> Agreed.
 Humanity (in the humane context) comes first at any cost.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="009">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Minor changes?
 you should print this bill.http://docs.house.gov/edlabor/AAHCA-BillText-071409.pdf
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="009" parent-url="009" url="010">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Why link to the full bill?
 If a regular Joe asks you how an airplane works you don't send them a full engineering schematic -- you send them a summary.
 Here is a summary of the House health care bill:http://edlabor.house.gov/blog/2009/10/affordable-health-care.shtmlAs you can see there is no communist plot.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="010" parent-url="010" url="011">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> I linked the bill because you said minor changes!
 This Is a total dismantling of our health care system.
 Its not a communist plot its socialism.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="011" parent-url="011" url="012">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Just because it's a big bill doesn't mean it gonna lead to big changes.
 That's just the way our messed up legislative process works.What makes you think they want to "dismantle" the health care system?
 That's so stupid.
 Why would anyone want to do that?
 Read the summary I posted.
 It's a good bill.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="012" parent-url="012" url="013">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Its a piece of shit bill!
 Howard Dean Thinks so (A Democrat)http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2009/12/16/AR2009121601906.htmlA DoctorMs.
 McCaughey is chairman of the Committee to Reduce Infection Deaths and a former Lt. Governor of New York state.http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704795604574519671055918380.htmlRead the whole thing not just the glossy summary oh wait its 1990 pages no one has read the whole thing not even the President.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="013" parent-url="013" url="014">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Your first link doesn't work.
 And if Howard Dean doesn't like the plan, it's obviously because he wants to domore.
 Howard Dean is strongly liberal; of course he wouldn't like this sensible, centrist bill.Your second link is an article from the freakin' Wall Street Journal, one of the most notoriously conservative publications in existence.
 How about I respond by linking to an equally biased article from the New York Times?
 Come on, this is no way to have an honest debate.And even then, why are you going on about theHousebill?
 That's not the one that's going to become law.
 It has to be reconciled with the more conservative Senate version first.Here are some unbiased links for you:http://www.factcheck.org/2009/08/twenty-six-lies-about-hr-3200/http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2010/jan/28/nancy-pfotenhauer/health-care-reform-does-not-increase-premiums-and-/
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="014" parent-url="014" url="015">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> "this is no way to have an honest debate"Your right!you cant read the first link so you assume what might be said and comment on it as fact, the second link you dismiss because its from a news paper, then you send me a link from the Annenberg Public Policy Center, now thats not biased!
 and a freakin' news paper.I'm going on about the house bill because the House writes the bills not the Senate.My question to you is why do you want me to pay for your health insurance?
 cant you fend for yourself?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="015" parent-url="015" url="016">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Ok, you fixed the link.
 And look at that, I was right.
 Howard Dean is calling for a public-option.
 Yes, a public-option would help in lots of ways -- but guess what?
 You asshats in the Republican party killed it!
 So yes, the bill doesn't do as much as good as it could, and that's why Dean is unhappy.Annenberg Public Policy Center is non-partisan.
 Just look at FactCheck.org.
 They clearly call out both parties.
 And not all newspapers are strongly biased.
 Some, like the Wall Street Journal and the New York Times, are famously biased, but not all."I'm going on about the house bill because the House writes the bills not the Senate."That's just wrong.
 Bills can be introduced in either the House or Senate.http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_Senate#Procedure"My question to you is why do you want me to pay for your health insurance?
 cant you fend for yourself?"I have insurance just like the majority of Americans.
 This bill is mainly about making some common sense changes to the system in order to make it work better.
 Yes, we are also offering a little aide to the very poor who can't afford insurance.
 How horrible!
 Do you honestly think people deserve to die if they can't afford health insurance?
 You disgust me.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="016" parent-url="016" url="017">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Can you name a person who has been turned away from an ER because they didn't have health insurance?
 You disgust me too!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="017" parent-url="017" url="018">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> People only go to the emergency room for stuff like heart attacks.
 What if someone has skin cancer and can't get treatment because they don't have insurance?
 You can't treat cancer in the emergency room!
 You bet your ass that person is going to die.Besides, guess who has to pay for their visit to the emergency room?
 All the rest of us!
 So why not give them insurance since we're going to end up paying either way?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="018" parent-url="018" url="019">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Thank You!
 you admit we are fucked either way!And you hurt my feelings when you said I disgust you.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="019" parent-url="019" url="020">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Well I'm sorry if the truth hurts.But what else can you say to someone who opposes a policy that will save lives at minimal cost?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="020" parent-url="020" url="021">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Minimal cost!
 A trillion hear and a trillion their.... sooner or later it adds up to real money.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="021" parent-url="021" url="022">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Bush's tax cuts for the rich cost twice as much as this will.http://www.ctj.org/pdf/bushtaxcutsvshealthcare.pdfWe can afford this.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="022" parent-url="022" url="023">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Why do you think that letting people keep the money they make "cost" anyone?
 the American people do not want this bill and if the boobs on the hill vote for it, it will "cost" them their jobs.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="022" parent-url="022" url="024">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> http://www.google.com/hostednews/canadianpress/article/ALeqM5h0QC7bditrEb3wYz_6_b-gsGGDxAOne more report regarding the Canadian health care system"I would've been criticized if I had stayed in Canada and had been perceived as jumping a line or a wait list.
 I accept that.
 That's public life," he said.
 Waiting list in Canada?
 wow that sucks if you have cancer!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="024" parent-url="024" url="025">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Canada has full-blown single payer coverage.
 Meaning people don't even need to buy insurance, they can just walk in and get whatever treatment they need at no cost.That's nowhere near what the Dems are proposing for the US.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="025" parent-url="025" url="026">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> At no cost?
 the Doctors work for free?
 no overhead at the hospital?
 that sounds great!
 another lie!
 the Canadian tax payer pays for it all ( the people who work)the highest tax bracket that exists in Canada is 46.41% that doesn't include the other taxes like a dump sticker, beach sticker, hunting tax, fishing tax and so on; add it up and they are paying 55 or 60% or more of their income to the government.
 move out of your parents basement and take care of yourself.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="026" parent-url="026" url="027">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> No cost meaning the patient doesn't pay directly.
 Duh.Income tax in Canada is not relevant to this debate.
 Also, you didn't cite a source for those numbers, so I'm going to assume you pulled them out your ass.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="027" parent-url="027" url="028">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mEJL2Uuv-oQ
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="027" parent-url="027" url="029">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Can you name a person who has been turned away from an ER because they didn't have health insurance?
 You disgust me too!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="027" parent-url="027" url="030">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Why no comment on this post?Universal Health care is so great the Canadians come to America for service if they can afford it, to bad if you cant.http://www.canadafreepress.com/index.php/article/19664Earlier this week it was revealed that Newfoundland and Labrador Premier Danny Williams was going to the United States for heart surgery.
 Like most Canadian politicians, Williams is a big proponent of Canada’s socialized health care system.The premier’s office has been tight lipped about exactly what is wrong with Williams and has only said that whatever treatment that he needs is not available in his home province.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="030" parent-url="030" url="031">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Another link to a bullshit conservative website, I see.Here's a more honest comparison:http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_Canadian_and_American_health_care_systemsAs you can see, when you judge fairly, the Canadian system is slightly better than ours, while being significantly less expensive.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="031" parent-url="031" url="032">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">WB40</user>
				<text> Wikipedia is not an honest comparison.
 Mainly because any idiot can edit it.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="032" parent-url="032" url="033">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> That's what makes it a good source.
 Every sentence has been debated to death.
 All the facts are backed up by reliable sources.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="033" parent-url="033" url="034">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> You might want to check out the jessald(1549) page on Wiki.
 I didn't believe it but if you say its reliable than who am I to argue.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="034" parent-url="034" url="035">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> I'm guessing you made a page as a joke?
 I can't find it, it must have been taken down right away.Like I said, everything in the article is backed up by citations from reliable sources.
 Go read them if you don't trust the article.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="035" parent-url="035" url="036">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> I wouldn't make a page like that I have a little class!
 Has your opinion changed following the Presidents talk with the Republicans or shall I say talk at the Republicans?
 I didn't see the whole thing but I listened more then the President did.
 Your thoughts?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="036" parent-url="036" url="037">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Yes, my opinion has changed.
 I am now even more convinced than ever that the Republican party is completely full of shit.One Republican says, "This program is increasing entitlement spending too much!"
 Thenten seconds lateranother one says, "This program is cutting Medicare too much!"Which do you want?Less coverage or more?
 Pick one you idiots!Then they say the want to "start over".
 Bullshit!
 It's so obvious what they mean is delay, delay, delay, just so they can watch the American people get fed up with the Democrats.The sad thing is they could beimprovingthe bill by negotiating with Dems to keep costs down.
 The Dems would be all over that.
 It would be good for the American people.
 But all those fuckers care about is their poll numbers.The whole Republican party is just a bunch of stinkin assholes.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="037" parent-url="037" url="038">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> Dude you have some serious anger issues!
 I'm not a Dr. but I would recommend a vacation.
 (I think the Republicans will pay for your trip) good luck with your therapy.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="037" parent-url="037" url="039">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">usps</user>
				<text> wikipedia?
 what did you write the post your self?
 come on.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="037" parent-url="037" url="040">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">JakeJ</user>
				<text> Who wrote that "summary"?
 Are they liberal?
 Just wondering.Also, don't belittle people that don't want nationalized healthcare by saying we think it's a "communist plot".
 Your words.
 Another strawman.
 l:But hey, I'm sure you'll scramble up some link of an idiot saying it's a communist plot.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="040" parent-url="040" url="041">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> It's from a bi-partisan committee.
 If you have a better summary, I'm happy to use it.I'll stop belittling you guys when you stop being stupid.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="041" parent-url="041" url="042">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">JakeJ</user>
				<text> "It's from a bi-partisan committee.
 If you have a better summary, I'm happy to use it."I just think you wouldn't be calling it bipartisan if you disagreed with it.
 None the less, I would still like my answer.
 Are the people on that comity liberal?
 Or do they at least lean left?
 I'm only Curious.And just because I don't trust a summary doesn't mean I have my own better summary.
 That's a childish response, of course I don't have one.
 What makes you think it's valid to ask me that?"I'll stop belittling you guys when you stop being stupid."Let me get this straight, You'll stop saying we're saying something we're not saying, ..
 when we stop saying it?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="042" parent-url="042" url="043">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Come on Jake, you can do research just as well as I can.
 Don't be lazy.I know little about the committee.
 I just googled "health-care summary" or something and found the page.
 Here's a list of the committee members:http://edlabor.house.gov/about/members/
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="043" parent-url="043" url="044">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">JakeJ</user>
				<text> Yeah lol I am kind of lazy about that.There's more Democrats than Republicans on the list so I guess I was partly right.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="045">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">RevKristine</user>
				<text> Here in Australia we have subsidised health care.
 It's not free, but we pay a lot less out of pocket than people in the US, and people who have low or no income can sometimes get the government to cover the entire cost of their medical bills, and the major portion of their medications.
 It doesn't teach people to be lazy.
 What it does is allow people to get a good standard of health care on a regular basis.
 This means that people go to their doctor at the start of their illness, rather than waiting until they're so ill that they need emergency care.We do pay for our health care through our taxes and I don't think health care should be free, however there are some major benefits to subsidised health care.
 It reduces the amount of down time due to illness for the low income workers, and makes them more able-bodied.
 It also reduces the chances of people catching communicable diseases.
 If anything, it means that people work more, not less.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="046">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Saffron</user>
				<text> ...Or you die!The minimum length for an argument is 50 characters.
 The purpose of this restriction is to cut down on the amount of dumb jokes, so we can keep the quality of debate and discourse as high as possible.
</text>
			</comment>
		</comments>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>