<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:lj="http://www.livejournal.org/rss/lj/1.0/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
	<title>AndrewJ</title>
	<item>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">000</guid>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 01:14:00 EST</pubDate>
		<title>Should_tobacco_be_banned</title>
		<link>000</link>
		<description> why do people need tobacco its killing them....thats so stupid
</description>
		<comments url="000">
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="000" parent-url="000" url="001">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">MKIced</user>
				<text> A lot of people try it out of peer pressure when they're young and can't stop because it's addicting.
 Nicotine is an addicting substance and the main component of tobacco.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="001" parent-url="001" url="002">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">AndrewJ</user>
				<text> heres an idea don't give in to peer pressure..... peer pressure is another reason it should be banned.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="001" parent-url="001" url="003">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Which is one of the reasons for why it should be banned, not continued.My main concern is second hand smoke.
 What do you call killing someone without their consent?
 Murder.
 That is not legal so why should tobacco if 2nd hand smoke kills hundreds of thousands a year?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="003" parent-url="003" url="004">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">MKIced</user>
				<text> Secondhand smoke is preventable.
 Can't the innocent people walk away from the smokers?
 And if they're in a car, they can roll down the windows.
 Besides, it's illegal in most public places (and cars too, when there's a child in the back?).
 The tobacco industry is too lucrative to be stopped.
 The answer here is reform, not banishment.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="004" parent-url="004" url="005">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Cant innocent people just not live in the hood?
 Is it the shooters fault that they were in their part of the ghetto?
 According to your logic they should of just avoided the bad area.
 What about a child living at a home where smoke is constantly in the air ( smoke lingers even when there doesn't appear to be any making 2nd hand smoke still a factor ).
 Considering how many people DIE a year due to second hand smoke I think it should be closely looked at.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="005" parent-url="005" url="006">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> I mostly agree with you, except I don't think the government is responsible for saving individuals from themselves.
 I think the reason we should ban tobacco is that smokers cause harm tootherpeople by using up our health care resources.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="006" parent-url="006" url="007">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> I definitely agree, 2nd hand smoke is a horrible way to die it should be considered as murder.
 Here's a joke!So a man gets diagnosed with lung cancer by his doctor, the man asks if this was of natural occurrences or if he was near radiation ( jokingly of course ), the doctor looks at him and says you can't fool me this report says you smoke cigarettes!
 The man utterly confused says no my wife does!Wasn't that hilarious!
 The man DIES A COUPLE YEARS LATER!!!!
 Punch line?
 Who needs 1 when you have GOLD LIKE THAT!!!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="007" parent-url="007" url="008">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jinond</user>
				<text> wow, i love totally unsupported claims.There is zero evidence that second hand smoke causes cancer.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="008" parent-url="008" url="009">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Wow I love ignorant morons here is a little something from just about everyone who is the law with health and cancer.Does exposure to secondhand smoke cause cancer?Yes.
 The U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the U.S. National Toxicology Program (NTP), the U.S. Surgeon General, and the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC) have classified secondhand smoke as a known human carcinogen (cancer-causing agent) .Inhaling secondhand smoke causes lung cancer in nonsmoking adults (4).
 Approximately 3,000 lung cancer deaths occur each year among adult nonsmokers in the United States as a result of exposure to secondhand smoke (2).
 The Surgeon General estimates that living with a smoker increases a nonsmoker’s chances of developing lung cancer by 20 to 30 percent (4).Some research suggests that secondhand smoke may increase the risk of breast cancer, nasal sinus cavity cancer, and nasopharyngeal cancer in adults, and leukemia, lymphoma, and brain tumors in children (4).
 Additional research is needed to learn whether a link exists between secondhand smoke exposure and these cancers.That is fromhttp://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/factsheet/Tobacco/ETS,yeah CANCER.GOVSo um OWNED and get the hell out of here.
 That was worth the first down vote since the new update came out.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="008" parent-url="008" url="010">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">ncher3</user>
				<text> i think ur making loads of sence and i am soo whith u cause i am a second hand smokerfrom the day i was born i now have asmer
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="009" parent-url="009" url="011">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">lawnman</user>
				<text> Should Tobacco be banned?Hey, wolfmanBefore I begin, you already know what my position is about banning tobacco; I opposed your argument, but more on that later.The first matter at hand is that the entirety of your argument completely missed the point of your debate, your argument answers the question: Is smoking tobacco healthy?
 And nothing in your argument syllogistically proves that tobacco should be banned.
 You might of said something like: “Should the smoking of tobacco be banned?” Had you of done so, there would be an agreement of the question and your argument.
 No, I am not denying your claims about the statistics of tobacco smokers, I am indicating to you that those statistics are irrelevant, off point, to the question of the debate.
 Banning the smoking of tobacco and banning tobacco are separate questions.Now, in response to your argument, regardless of the question you attempted to answer, I will respond to the argument and not address the question of the debate.“Smoking tobacco kills more than alcohol, drug abuse, car crashes, murders, suicides, and fires combined.
 World-wide some 3 million people die from smoking each year, 1 every 10 seconds.
 Smokers are more than 20 times more likely to develop lung cancer than non-smokers, and smoking can lead to a host of other health problems, including emphysema and heart disease.”The act of smoking tobacco does not kill anybody.
 Your argument begins with an undistributed subject, smoking.
 Are you meaning: “all smoking” or “some smoking”?
 The predicate is also undistributed.
 You claim as though the quantity of people supposedly killed by smoking is reason enough to ban tobacco, while at the same time ignoring other statistical supremacies such as 42 million abortions per year in the world.
 Nor does it speak of medical complications that kill more people than smoking tobacco.
 If you are going to use statistics to validate your argument, I will tell you the order in priority by which things should be banned.
 Smoking will not be high on the list of banning.Moreover, men who smoke an occasional cigar or pipe are unlikely to die because of smoking.
 Therefore, some smoking is not a proven cause of death.
 People who do not smoke tobacco die of the same diseases as smokers.
 Some smokers die by causes that are not related to smoking.Tobacco has many other uses and abuses other than smoking.Also, do you honestly think a politician has the right to govern vices?
 The presupposition that all smokers smoke in the vicinity of others who smoke not is jumping to conclusion.
 The presupposition that I shall die of smoking, rules out my death by drowning.There are many other issues of your argument that are less than logical, allow us to consider the above before we address the others.I told you as an ally I would challenge you as an ally.
 So don’t think I intend offence.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="011" parent-url="011" url="012">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> My point of the debate was should tobacco be banned.
 My reasoning?
 When people smoke tobacco the chemical nicotine physically addicts them to the drug, therefore in most cases making them addicted.
 Then after smoking for a good couple years most people start to lose their physical abilities by a slight margin.
 Then after smoking for lets say 25 years and now they are in their 40s.
 Many people will come down with lung cancer, emphysema, etc etc. My reasoning is that the government bans the smoking of pot, cocaine, meth, etc etc. Is it not the governments responsibility to not allow people to do drugs ( or anything else ) that subject other people to injury?My main point is second hand smoke.
 That is my main reasoning for why smoking tobacco should be banned.
 People that are being subjected to second hand smoke are doing so against their own will.
 That is wrong in many counts.
 I never listed the amount of people that do not die from smoking I only listed the amount of people that DO smoke and die because of health complications do to smoking tobacco.I addressed my debate topic.
 The reason it should be banned is it physically addicts people to the substance.
 Kills more than alcohol, drug abuse, car crashes, murders, suicides and fires combined.
 It kills people that are merely subjected to the smoke.
 Now tell me how I missed my own debate topic.
 What the hell do abortions have to do with anything?
 We are talking about tobacco.
 Do not count abortions as murder as the fetus feels nothing up to a certain point in the pregnancy.
 That is a different debate all in itself.Going by your once in awhile outlook on smoking a pipe or a cigar.
 What about smoking some crack every once in awhile?
 If I shoot up some crack once a week I am probably not going to die now am I?
 Does the government ban crack?
 They sure do.
 Does crack kill nearly as many as tobacco?
 Hell no.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="012" parent-url="012" url="013">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">lawnman</user>
				<text> I'll grant you a pass this time because it's your debate and I see no benefit for you by another rebuttal.
 I think you over-looked some key premises, also consider reading my argument again.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="012" parent-url="012" url="014">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">AndrewJ</user>
				<text> I fully agree.The second hand thing was great.
 so yeah.....................
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="013" parent-url="013" url="015">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Pdubstisdar</user>
				<text> Yes, you can challenge his statiostics, but whether they are totally correct is not the point.
 The fact of the matter is, smoking undeniably kills millions each year.
 That is the statistic that should unanimously decide whether smoking or any form of tobacco should be legal.
 DEFINATELY NOT!!!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="012" parent-url="012" url="016">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">iamdavidh</user>
				<text> And like alcohol, crack, marijuana, cocaine, etc,making it illegal won't stop one person who wants to partake from taking a puff.Meanwhile, a huge source of revenue will be lost.
 A huge new expense will emerge from trying to enforce the law, lock up the criminals, and keep them in jail.Prohibition has never worked, it didn't work with alcohol, it doesn't work with drugs, it wouldn't work with tobacco.
 The only difference is, instead of legitimate businesses and government getting their cut, all of the profits go to gangsters, murderers, and terrorists.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="016" parent-url="016" url="017">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> True but crack and marijuana are already banned.
 Tobacco kills millions MORE per year than drug overdoses per year.
 Prohibition of alcohol didn't work back when we had wagons, who expected it to?
 I'd say it works with cocaine since there is a very slim number of crack heads on this planet.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="017" parent-url="017" url="018">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">iamdavidh</user>
				<text> well, crack and cocaine just happen to be less popular drugs, that's all.
 the amounts of all drugs consumed has always risen on a steady incline with little bumps here and there.
 It's a mistake to think that, somehow the government is more capable now than they were then of enforcing prohibition.
 There was a time when opium based drugs were legal.
 No more or less people took them then compared to now.
 A drug called Salvia is now legal, as states make it illegal, you'll see that it will not one bit decrease the amount of Salvia consumed.Prohibition is just something to make puritans feel better, and a way of ignoring a problem.
 It simply doesn't work.
 If one wants to combat drugs, the only things that work are education, and rehabilitation.
 And at the end of the day, someone who wants to take any drug, whether it be tobacco or alcohol, or crack-cocaine, is going to,instead of wasting billions fighting it, legalize it all, and spend millions (as apposed to billions) on rehab for those who want to quit and education.At the end of the day, the government will make money on taxation, the prisons will be all but empty, and crimes related to drugs will take a nose-dive, as the profits are taken out of the hands of gangsters and murderers, and into the hands of legitimate businesses.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="018" parent-url="018" url="019">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Crack and cocaine are not available in your average drug store.
 Whether or not it is illegal it is hard to obtain.Tobacco is as easy as it gets to obtain, why?
 It is legal.
 If the only way to get tobacco was on the streets I guarantee you a lot less people would be smoking tobacco.Drug related crimes would take a nose dive sure.
 Children doing drugs would have the opposite effect.
 Now they can have their brothers, sisters, and older friends go into Walgreens and buy them a nickel bag?
 Doesn't sound ideal at all to me.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="019" parent-url="019" url="020">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">iamdavidh</user>
				<text> I think you're overestimating the difficulty a person addicted to drugs has getting that drug significantly.But I see that everyone basically is attempting to make the same points, and it's been gone over quite a few times.
 There's nothing I can say beyone what I or anyone else already has at this point I think.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="020" parent-url="020" url="021">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">tje0454</user>
				<text> first off i agree with you about where the revenue would go if tobacco was banned/made illegal.
 There would be another drug anyone could get off a dealer.
 And just because people will still smoke tobacco if it became illegal doesn't mean that it should simply be legal.
 But just because revenue will be lost by corporations doesnt automatically mean that something shouldnt be banned.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="019" parent-url="019" url="022">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">PrayerFails</user>
				<text> Tobacco products should never be banned because ultimately it is a person's choice.
 The government already makes enough choices for the general public.
 If the government banned tobacco, people would find any necessary means in buying, selling, and using tobacco products despite the ban.
 This is reminds me of the war on drugs.
 It would be prohibition all over again except tobacco.Tobacco was used as currency in the colonial period of 1612-1776, so even with a ban, tobacco will always have great value.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="022" parent-url="022" url="023">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> What in the world does tobacco being used as currency in the colonial period have to do with anything?Tobacco products should never be banned because ultimately it is a person's choice.Sure the smoker's choice, not the person inhaling second hand smoke.If the government banned tobacco, people would find any necessary means in buying, selling, and using tobacco products despite the ban.Somepeople would find any necessary mean, just likesomepeople find ways of obtaining cocaine and other illegal substances.
 If it was banned it would diminish the numbers, not raise them.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="023" parent-url="023" url="024">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">orangepeel</user>
				<text> Sure the smoker's choice, not the person inhaling second hand smoke.That's why smoking is banned in many public places.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="024" parent-url="024" url="025">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> That doesn't prevent people from contracting different illnesses correlated to second hand smoke ...
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="025" parent-url="025" url="026">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">JBXXX</user>
				<text> Since you seem to like statistics why don't you find one that actually means anything.
 Like what percentage of those people that died from smoking didn't regret smoking.
 Tobacco isn't crack, many smokers actually enjoy smoking and understand the risks involved.
 While secondhand smoke is a killer, if someone is obeying the law and smoking outdoors there's no reason they shouldn't be allowed to choose to do so.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="026" parent-url="026" url="027">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Lets ask the couple hundred thousand kids that contract lung cancer from second hand smoke.
 Did they regret smoking?
 Oh wait they never smoked, so I guess your right they couldn't regret it.My whole point is that it should be against the law, who cares if a smoker understands the risks involved.
 I am talking about that kid who is inhaling the smoke against his/her will.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="027" parent-url="027" url="028">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jacksmith</user>
				<text> well we could say the same about alcohol lets ask a couple hundred thousand kids born with fas because there mothers were drinking while pregnant its been proven how many kids suffer from domestic violence guess what most domestic violence is caused by alcohol as well as the carnage on the road and many cancers so lets ban alcohol kids and adults would be better off as well
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="027" parent-url="027" url="029">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">chanc112</user>
				<text> Illegalising tobacco wouldn't stop the use of it, just like marijuana.
 marijuana is banned, still it's really widely used.
 It will cause more bad than good if we prohibit tobacco.
 all it will do is cause more crime (e.g criminal organisations like mafias).The prohibition of alcohol in the US 1920-1933 was a complete failure.
 It will just be the same, but a lot worse.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="027" parent-url="027" url="030">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">fukdawolfman</user>
				<text> Dawolfman you are a fucking idiot.
 tobacco shouldnt be banned ya its bad and everything but its none of governments business.
 our country was founded on having the least government control possible.
 Your just asking to have a socialist country.
 Il bet your some kind of obama lover you jackass
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="030" parent-url="030" url="031">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Fukdawolfman, you sir are a fucking idiot.I would make an attempt of understanding your lunacy but just by going from your name I can see that arguing with you would be the same as arguing with the chair I'm sitting in.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="030" parent-url="030" url="032">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">TERMINATOR</user>
				<text> Most idiots like you don't even know what socialism is. Don't go around using words you don't know - I'd say about three letters should be the maximum.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="030" parent-url="030" url="033">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">flymike</user>
				<text> no you are a fucking idiot, you want the least government control possible.??
 government=electedcapitalism=anything for profit+not electedhaha you thing you are free coz your country is called a ''democracy'' ???
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="031" parent-url="031" url="034">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">meme123</user>
				<text> smoking is one of the number 1 killers in the world.
 it not only kills the person smoking, but the people around it.
 Smoking gives you cancer and other health problems.
 once you see someone die from smoking what makes you continue to smoke.
 it doesn't make sense.smoking should be banned in all public places to reduce the number of people killed each year.
 no body wants to be eating while someone is smoking right behind them.the government should make smoking illegal and take responsibility of the fact that they are contributing to the deaths.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="035">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Not true, are you forgetting about wars?
 We don't use sticks now do we.
 We use guns.
 Tobacco has not killed nearly as many people as guns have all in all.
 Murder and gun incidents are at just a couple thousand a year in the USA while tobacco is nearly to a million just in the US.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="035" parent-url="035" url="036">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">darkrye2</user>
				<text> Actually, tobacco has killed more people than all of the american wars combined.
 PWNED
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="037">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Warlin</user>
				<text> I don't think the liberals support smoking, more or less the CHOICE to smoke.
 People who decide to take up smoking know full well what they're going to be doing to themselves.
 They're reminded constantly every day by their friends and their family and people they don't even know.
 Their habit is banned from restaurants and public forums in most states.These people KNOW what they're doing to themselves.
 As long as there's a market for tobacco, there's going to be someone selling it.I think instead of banning tobacco we should raise the price per carton and put higher restrictions on it.
 We should enforce a more blatant warning logo.
 We should make it a crime to smoke in the presence of a child.
 Ban nicotine, you know, all of that jazz.Why should the guy who smokes three packs a day ruin it for the guy who has the occasional cigarette(once or twice a week) when he drinks?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="038">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">PrayerFails</user>
				<text> Tobacco products should never be banned because ultimately it is a person's choice.
 The government already makes enough choices for the general public.
 If the government banned tobacco, people would find any necessary means in buying, selling, and using tobacco products despite the ban.
 This is reminds me of the war on drugs.
 It would be prohibition all over again except tobacco.Tobacco was used as currency in the colonial period of 1612-1776, so even with a ban, tobacco will always have great value.What will happen with a ban on tobacco?
 A black Market similar to that of illegal drugs now.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="039">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">sweetiesarah</user>
				<text> VERY TRUE SMOKING IS DEADLY WHY WOULD YOU WANT TO KILL ALL OR THOSE THINGS....YOUR WALET AND YOUR LIFE IS THE WORST...POLLUTING THE AIR IS BAD TOO!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="040">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Bohemian</user>
				<text> The adverse health affects of drinking Drain-O greatly outweighs any satisfaction one may gain from drinking it, so by the same reasoning should we not also outlaw the consumption of every harmful substance?Isn't it up to the individual to decide whether to engage in a dangerous activity?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="040" parent-url="040" url="041">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jmih666</user>
				<text> No, that’s not the reasoning.
 This argument focuses on the effect, not the act itself.
 There are more stakeholders than just the person performing the activity.
 It’s an utilitarian argument stating that the choice on the matter needs to benefit the majority.
 You can look at this dilemma from all sorts of moral and ethical perspectives.
 You state that the act itself is bad and laws should apply on all similar situations even if they cannot be compared.
 That is one way to look at it but it would make life pretty grim, unnecessarily complicated and unpractical.As for the decision of individuals to engage in dangerous activities.
 It is indeed their freedom to do so as long as they are capable to make that choice and harm no others (which is easily done).
 However, the governments that individuals are subjected to have the moral duty to keep its people out of harm’s way, as far as it is reasonably possible, through laws and regulations.
 It is up to governments how they apply those laws.
 And they will try to keep as many people as possible happy, which is pretty much an utilitarian approach.
 Likely the ones that bring the most cash.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="041" parent-url="041" url="042">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Bohemian</user>
				<text> However, the governments that individuals are subjected to have the moral duty to keep its people out of harm’s wayNot from themselves it isn't.It’s an utilitarian argument stating that the choice on the matter needs to benefit the majority.Not when it infringes upon the rights of the minority.
 It is an inherently American Ideal that the government has no authority to limit or outlaw any action that does not cause undue harm to others.And they will try to keep as many people as possible happyDo you not accept the possibility that banning tobacco will make a lot of people unhappy, especially the smokers.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="043">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">vb123</user>
				<text> only poop heads smoke??
 Wow..what are you five?
 It should totally be the person smoking or not smoking making his/her own decision..yes, smoking does kill many people.
 But it also makes people happy, calms them down, etc. Everyone is clearly entitled to their own opinion but I do not think smoking should be banned..
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="044">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Kuklapolitan</user>
				<text> You know p6667, I've been smoking longer than most of you have been alive!
 The government taxes the hell out of tobacco and in all the years I've been smoking I've not been asked, NOT ONE TIME, if I need help with quitting and that our tax dollars might pay for it.
 I'd love to know where this money goes!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="045">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> Tobacco doesn't compare to other drugs in terms of buzz.
 Alcohol makes people feel good and more outgoing.
 Cigarettes don't do much besides getting you addicted and making you look like an idiot.Good point about tax dollars though.
 The War on Drugs has shown us the futility of trying to enforce a ban.
 But there are better ways to curb tobacco use, like taxing the hell of it, for example.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="045" parent-url="045" url="046">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">ThePyg</user>
				<text> tobacco is a stimulant while alcohol is a depressant.
 the only reason why people think they feel good is cause they get really stupid when shit faced.
 but really, anyone who has drunk a lot doesn't actually feel good.
 it's a party drink, and it fucks you up.it doesn't drown away emotions, just makes you sadder.
 this is why people are much more likely to commit suicide when intoxicated.smoking usually makes people feel like they can work harder while not altering their mind or body majorly.
 it's a boost, while relaxing them at the same time.plus, drinking and driving is a much bigger endemic than second hand smoke (mainly because second hand smoke has been proven as a TRUE killer).
 it's considered just as harmless as fueling up your own car.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="046" parent-url="046" url="047">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> "it doesn't drown away emotions, just makes you sadder."This sure as hell isn't what happens to me. Or anyone I know for that matter.
 Have you ever been drunk?When I'm drunk I feel confident, outgoing, and yes happy.Note that I'm talking like 6 beers here, not completely shitfaced.And even the few times I've gotten shitfaced I didn't feel sad, I felt basically the same as before, only drunker.
 You do understand that the word "depressant" doesn't mean "makes you feel sad", right?I can't tell what you're trying to say in your last paragraph.
 What do you mean by "second hand smoke has been proven as a TRUE killer"?Anyway, drinking and driving is indeed a problem -- that's why we have laws against it.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="047" parent-url="047" url="048">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">ThePyg</user>
				<text> right, put words in my mouth.it only makes you sad when you were sad to begin with.
 it eliminates ability to control your emotions.but w/e, i'm only going by what psychologists say.and, like i said, second hand smoke has not been proven as a true killer.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="048" parent-url="048" url="049">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">jessald</user>
				<text> "it eliminates ability to control your emotions."No, itdiminishesyour ability.
 Important difference.
 Even when I've gotten completely shitfaced, I have never violated any of my core values, and I've had opportunities to do so.
 I have done things I probably wouldn't have done sober, but that's half the point of getting drunk."and, like i said, second hand smoke has not been proven as a true killer."Actually, that's the opposite of what you said.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="049" parent-url="049" url="050">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">ThePyg</user>
				<text> o, then i've made a typo and i apologize.i meant to say "hasn't".
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="037" parent-url="037" url="051">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">doublejumper</user>
				<text> everything is killing us slowly.
 even oxgen kills us slowly.
 i think it should be banned because it has such a high mortality rate.
 not to mention my parents smoke and i dont want them dying anytime soon.
 plus it smells horribly!
 it sinks into my clothes and it won't come out!
 does anybody have a cure for that by the way?
 i was thinking something with baking soda but i dont know.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="051" parent-url="051" url="052">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">sparsely</user>
				<text> The only cure for the cigarette smell is to smoke for about 3 years, then you won't be able to smell it anymore.Buy them online from overseas, you won't have to pay our exorbitant taxes.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="051" parent-url="051" url="053">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Warlin</user>
				<text> My point is, if they ban cigarettes, they're just going to find another vice to get people hooked on.
 It won't change anything.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="053" parent-url="053" url="054">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> It wont change anything?
 Seriously?
 It would change the fate of more than 3 million people on this planet a year.
 If there was no tobacco my grandma would still be alive.Of course my grandmother and about 2.6 million of those smokers are smokers by choice the other 400k+ are second hand smoke inhalers.
 People that are subjected against their will to breathe all of the chemicals that are inside of that little paper wrapped carcinogenic treat.
 It would change the lives of a plethora of people.Another vice?
 Like what?
 There is no other vice like that of tobacco, it is the vice of the world.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="054" parent-url="054" url="055">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">Warlin</user>
				<text> You people just don't get it.
 I don't know why people can't see the bigger picture.Yeah, sure, okay, we ban tobacco.
 But what will happen?
 Two things: Either tobacco will resurface illegally and people will still smoke and chew and eventually the government will break down and give in like they did during the alcohol prohibition.
 OR, now here's the kicker and I'll say it again: People will find another vice.
 You see the fast food industry?
 The amount of heart attacks people get?
 What makes you think that today's smokers aren't prone to getting hooked on that shit?
 They'll feed it to their kids constantly and the obesity problem will probably rise.If you think the people who profit off of Tobacco have no way of finding something else to get people hooked on to die miserably you have a LOT to learn.If it happens, you'll see.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="055" parent-url="055" url="056">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> ...What smokers get hooked on is a chemical that MAKES your body PHYSICALLY ADDICTED to the substance the chemical is called nicotine.
 You must realize that people do many things illegally and on a very large scale.
 But if it was legal?
 A gargantuan scale.If tobacco is made illegal the number of smokers will dwindle that I guarantee.
 The food industry?
 Last time I checked McDonald's wasn't selling carcinogenic McNuggets.
 Or were they selling food that had a physically addictive substance in it?
 Oh wait no probably not.You as a person just don't get it.
 Nothing is going to replace cigarettes, if cigs are banned nobody is going to call anything legal that they come out with ' the new cigarettes'.
 Tobacco has been used since the Indians were around!
 And it has not gone out of fashion yet!Food is nothing like tobacco!
 If people are shoving their face in with food are they going to kill their family?
 Maybe their son or daughter due to second hand eating?
 No they are not.You are radiating incognizance to the point of where I find it unbearable!
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="057">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">K1ll3r</user>
				<text> Myth One is right, but the others....Myth 2: Tobacco is poison to the body and therefore is morally wrong.Counter Argument(1) Smoking stimulates open-mindedness as it allows conservatives to interact with risk takers and to explore alternative philosophies to life.(2) Smoking can be a catalyst in aiding people to be more focused on socially positive attitudes by taking a stance advocating quality of life vs economical productivityMyth 3: Smoking is bad for your health:Yeah, it is.(1) It prevents mental illnesses by providing an outlet for stress:True, but it harms your body, called video games or trolling.(2) It protects you from worser addictions such as:- sexual addiction leading to rape:How?- heroin addiction leading to broken homes:How?
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="038" parent-url="038" url="058">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Although tobacco kills 500,000 people a year, what good would it be to prohibit it when there is a drug in the cigarette that purposely is a addictive substance.
 It wouldn't change the fact many deaths will occur because people will still smoke.The purpose in prohibiting smoking isn't for the benefit of the smoker.
 I could care less about the smoker.
 My problem is with all the hundreds of thousands of kids that get diagnosed with lung cancer per year due to second hand smoke.
 It's not only kids either, smoking harms everyone around the smoker including the smoker him/her self.Also with something illegal it becomes harder to obtain, with it becoming harder to obtain the amount of smokers dwindles.
 When something is available to the masses through public stores then it is easy to obtain.
 When the only way to get a substance that is illegal is through back alleys it becomes harder to obtain.
 Get it?America would only have to relive the events of alcohol prohibition and live in the current events of illegal substances.
 This is black market.
 Society doesn't benefit from a black market.What are you talking about ...
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="059">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> This site is for intellectuals, not mental patients.
 Though we do appreciate you trying to sound like your IQ is above 40, it just isn't and there is no point in pretending.
 Thanks again, but if your brain can't process what a debate is just you know go frog gigging and muddin'.
 I am sure these are leisure activities even your small attention span can handle.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="030" parent-url="030" url="060">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> This site is for intellectuals, not mental patients.
 Though we do appreciate you trying to sound like your IQ is above 40, it just isn't and there is no point in pretending.
 Thanks again, but if your brain can't process what a debate is just you know go frog gigging and muddin'.
 I am sure these are leisure activities even your small attention span can handle.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="060" parent-url="060" url="061">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">TERMINATOR</user>
				<text> Looks like you angered somebody - and on the first day of your return, too.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="061" parent-url="061" url="062">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> Yeah, I'd say so.
 Judging by the quality of the " arguments " put forth, I wouldn't even give them the respect of calling him a ' somebody '.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="030" parent-url="030" url="063">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">PrayerFails</user>
				<text> Matter of fact, there shouldn't even be a age limit.
 You should be able to smoke at any age.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="064">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> This site is for intellectuals, not mental patients.
 Though we do appreciate you trying to sound like your IQ is above 40, it just isn't and there is no point in pretending.
 Thanks again, but if your brain can't process what a debate is just you know go frog gigging and muddin'.
 I am sure these are leisure activities even your small attention span can handle.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="065">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> This site is for intellectuals, not mental patients.
 Though we do appreciate you trying to sound like your IQ is above 40, it just isn't and there is no point in pretending.
 Thanks again, but if your brain can't process what a debate is just you know go frog gigging and muddin'.
 I am sure these are leisure activities even your small attention span can handle.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="066">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">DaWolfman</user>
				<text> This site is for intellectuals, not mental patients.
 Though we do appreciate you trying to sound like your IQ is above 40, it just isn't and there is no point in pretending.
 Thanks again, but if your brain can't process what a debate is just you know go frog gigging and muddin'.
 I am sure these are leisure activities even your small attention span can handle.
</text>
			</comment>
			<comment date-time="2005-12-29 01:14 AM EST" parent-id="-1" parent-url="-1" url="067">
				<user blog_url="NA" profile_url="NA">infection0</user>
				<text> This is a comment without porpose.
 Please stick to intelligent answers.
</text>
			</comment>
		</comments>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>